AS YOU STOOD BY
EP 01
EUN-SU
You have gone off route.
-I'll take this. Gift wrapped, please.
-Sure.
Hey, Hui-su.
I'll be at the restaurant soon.
Eun-su, I'm sorry. I'm still at home.
Why? Is something up?
I had to meet
with my publisher unexpectedly.
Thank you to all our customers here
at the Lavie Department Store…
-Hui-su, you said you're at home, right?
-Yes, I'll be in touch after my deadline.
We are running a special promotion
for newlyweds on popular brands…
Sounds good.
All right. We have high hopes
since you, our top performers,
are stationed at this year's
most carefully curated watch booth.
Go get them, guys.
You've got this.
How's this one?
If you're looking for something
more glamorous, how about…
Okay, thank you.
Would you like to try this on?
It's been a while
since I've been greeted in Chinese.
That's a relief,
since I can be of more help in Korean.
I'm glad to help you.
Would you like to try this on?
I haven't told you what I have my eye on.
It's a premium model set with 90 diamonds,
and it's one of the slimmest
automatic watches in the world.
A nice and simple pitch.
A shame that it's such a good fit.
Does it not suit me?
I wouldn't say that,
but in your case,
I think this model would suit you better.
No diamonds?
Even if it doesn't have gold,
platinum, or any diamonds,
with your presence,
even a steel watch speaks volumes.
Right.
Still, men should wear diamonds.
Huh? Why is this…
Where could it…
Is something up?
It's gone.
What is?
It should be here, but it's not.
What isn't here?
The premium limited edition model.
The one with a diamond bezel.
Oh no, what should we do?
-What do we do?
-Hang on.
I'm the only one
who handled this watch today,
so this doesn't involve you two.
I'll deal with it.
Here.
-Could you zoom in?
-Sure.
He looked right at the security camera.
We should notify the police.
Then I'd need to notify our division head.
Assistant Manager Jo,
first check the invite list.
He came as a guest of Chairman Ma
from Shanghai. He's not on the list.
It's not like
we can directly ask Chairman Ma.
Please try it on…
Hello, Chairman.
Have you been well?
Chairman Wang.
I think I can find him.
Thank you.
JIN SO-BAEK
Hello.
My God!
-How many trucks are coming in today?
-Two box trucks in the afternoon.
I haven't notified our division head yet,
so we can't get the police involved.
Just drop him a hint
that we know he's the one who took it.
Boss.
There was an error
with the Lao Gan Ma order.
It should have been ten,
but we ordered 35.
Three…
-Just 15.
-Just 15?
Okay, I'll order 15.
Hello.
You're here early.
You haven't had breakfast, have you?
I know a good hangover soup joint.
It's on me.
I'll take back the watch
and buy breakfast.
I guess I'll be skipping breakfast today.
Man, I'm starving.
Hey, Jenny.
Are you checking expiration dates?
President Chen Shaobo.
Could you please show me
that watch from yesterday?
What was that just now? Chen, what?
Just call me Jin So-baek or President Jin.
Much easier to pronounce.
What even was that?
The watch isn't on me right now.
If it's at home--
I sent it somewhere as a present.
I'm sorry?
What? It's not like I sold it.
If they like it,
I'll purchase it right away.
And if they don't like it?
I'll return it immediately.
To your department store.
You were invited by Chairman Ma
from Shanghai and know Chairman Wang,
so we've decided to give you
a day's time, President Jin.
If it isn't returned today,
you must buy it according to store policy.
Let's do that.
I'll hear back today anyway.
You're jumping through
all these hoops for me.
If the purchase ends up happening,
I'll make sure it goes through you.
I'm Jo Eun-su.
Assistant Manager Jo Eun-su,
I'll ensure you get the sale.
Until then, I must ask you
for your written word.
A piece of paper means nothing.
If you're so anxious,
don't mind me and just call the cops.
They're doing construction out there.
Do you know
how many exits this building has?
One there.
Dear me.
The first thing to do when collecting debt
is check the number and location of exits.
You've got grit but no finesse.
I am tenacious though.
Today's not over,
so could I please get it in writing?
I've found carrying a knife
to be more effective than paper.
I don't have a knife.
THREE
-Enjoy!
-Thank you!
One floor up
from the Jingang Chinese Market.
Take it.
HUI-SU
SORRY, I CAN'T TALK RIGHT NOW
They knew it was a bribe,
but they insisted it should be a gift.
That thieving bastard.
You think I switched it out?
Not you but that thieving bastard.
The watch is clean,
but there's a small scratch on the strap.
Unlikely. I checked the thing myself.
I bet it will wipe away.
We can't wipe it down
and sell it to another customer.
So, Mr. Jin, you'll need to purchase it.
The day isn't over yet.
You could just buy the strap.
It's expensive
because it's premium croc leather
and only 100 are made a year,
but it suits that watch
you're wearing now.
I can change the strap for you now.
I don't want the strap.
Let's settle at three million.
You'll know that's a decent deal.
My apologies.
So you lack both finesse and acumen.
I'd have asked for five million.
And I'd never have stolen…
taken it in the first place.
Why go to such lengths
when you're still on a payroll?
My goal is to be promoted to an executive.
I'm not one to strike a deal
that doesn't benefit me.
JINGANG CHINESE MARKET
Why did you steal the watch?
I told you earlier
that I borrowed it temporarily.
I couldn't tell from the outside,
but this isn't just a small market.
You're the president
of this huge trading company.
I wasn't sure
they'd be signing the contract.
You want me to carry all that cash
and buy it, then return it?
You speak nonsense with such confidence
that you almost had me
nodding in agreement.
Jo Eun-su.
Are there times…
when you unleash…
the psycho inside you?
Seems to me like you've always held back
your emotions to prevent that.
Why don't you come and work for me?
No, thanks.
If you hand me your watch,
I'll change the strap for you.
The sound of these tiles.
It's calming when a lot is on your mind.
On second thought,
I'm the one who was just ripped off,
so I need this more.
Clatter.
Clatter…
I'm clumsy with my hands.
Indeed, you are.
I bet Hui-su would be great at this.
My friend. She's great with her hands.
Great at writing and drawing.
She's a storybook author.
Storybook?
The sort of stories that end with
"and they lived happily ever after."
-The watch strap--
-Switch it out next time.
Let me at least carry this for you.
That man, Jin So-baek.
The manager was worried
since we had no info on him.
I mean, I knew you'd do it,
but to solve it on your own…
Wow, I truly respect you.
Cut it out.
Hey, can you leave this by my station?
Sure.
Hello.
Hello, Eun-su.
Hello. Are you well?
Of course.
This.
Would it suit Hui-su?
Yes, it's stunning.
But it's not her birthday
or your wedding anniversary.
-I get her gifts now and then.
-You mean often.
He's one of our regulars.
I didn't know Hui-su came here often.
I come alone to make the purchases.
Hui-su likes surprises.
She does?
She hates not knowing, so she skips
to the last page of mystery novels.
All wrapped for you now.
Great, thank you. I'll see you soon.
After you.
All right, see you.
He's become much gentler.
HUI-SU
MRS. KANG HUI-YEON
Hello, ma'am.
Ma'am!
Are you hurt?
Please zip me up.
Of course.
I thought you, Eun-su…
would be different.
I…
Customer privacy is our VIP sales team's
top priority…
Sir.
You were in here?
With a jacket on…
you'd look more elegant.
Good.
You'll just wear that out.
Please do, ma'am.
What do you think, Ms. Jo?
It suits her.
You do have a good eye.
The boutique next door
has the perfect shoes for this outfit.
Could I take her for a look?
You know my wife's shoe size.
Just have them delivered.
Will do, sir.
There are a lot of shoes here.
What about those?
Yes, those will do.
They ate up a whole 50 minutes.
Why did she have to do that in our store?
My lips are sealed.
Did something happen
with President Kwon Seong-cheol?
Why do you ask?
He just preordered
500 year-end gift sets in your name.
Under my name?
I hear you helped his wife today.
That Mr. Kwon…
I knew he'd been one of our top ten VIPs
over the past ten years, but wow.
Thanks to you, we won't have to worry
about this quarter's numbers.
GANGCHEOL JIUJITSU
Wait, tap!
Even if he doesn't shut me up,
being discreet
and playing dumb are my forte.
Jo Eun-su.
I'm surprised you held out,
being so distracted.
Only because you let me.
MOM'S BIRTHDAY TOMORROW
TELL HER I CAN'T VISIT
CUSTOMER: KANG HUI-YEON
LIVES IN HANNAM-DONG
I thought you, Eun-su…
would be different.
MOM
Eun-su?
Eun-su. What is it?
Hey, did I wake you?
No, I wasn't asleep yet. Is something up?
I won't be able to make it
for your birthday.
I know. You're busy. Come some other time.
All right. Good night.
But what were you doing up so late?
I was just
drinking soju.
On your own?
Yes.
Well done, you.
And you? What are you doing up?
For a young woman like me,
it's the early evening.
I was drinking beer.
Well done, you.
Good night.
These days…
I walk in the park with your dad
every evening.
And?
I just thought I'd tell you.
You must be tired. Get some sleep.
I'm here too early.
How…
how come you're here?
I didn't prepare any food.
I brought you cake.
You're here?
You still store your knives in there?
Isn't it inconvenient?
It's okay. I find this most convenient.
Do you stay at home during the day?
I hang out with the ladies
in the neighborhood,
but they always want to go
to the bathhouse.
And?
Do you join them?
Why would I when I can bathe at home?
You have always disliked
public bathhouses.
I bet I'm the only one who never went
to a bathhouse with their mom as a kid.
While we're on the subject,
shall we go tomorrow morning?
Eun-hyeok called to say he's coming.
How many times are you gonna taste it?
Mom, I'm home.
Dad, I'm home.
Mom, here.
Let's see.
My, you're made of steel.
Bring out the cake.
Let me clear the food away first.
Cake's also food.
Bring it out.
Let's get the candles over with.
Department store cakes sure are something.
It's absolutely exquisite.
We should digest a bit,
light the candles, and take some photos--
You sure talk a lot.
Dad.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Gye-sun
Mouthing off to me over some measly cake.
They never show their precious faces
for my birthday but show up for yours.
Are you feeling smug? Are you?
-Mom.
-Are you enjoying this?
Do you still hit Mom?
Eun-su, that's not it.
I was coming down to go to the toilet…
Is that why you hide the kitchen knives?
So he can't get to them?
Why, you little…
You've been telling her such things?
Do you know Mom tried to kill herself
when I was in high school?
Eun-su.
What?
What happened that day still haunts me.
It drives me crazy.
THE YEAR 2008
Mom!
Mom, no!
Mom! Please don't!
Mom, you can't!
Eun-su.
Did Dad hit you again?
No, that's not it.
He doesn't hit me.
Does he still hit you
when we aren't home?
You can't tell Eun-hyeok. Or Dad.
Mom.
Jong-gu kept me gaming all night.
You're already leaving?
-Yes.
-I'm going to shower and head out too.
Let's go together.
I'm giving Dad a lift.
See you.
About…
what happened yesterday…
The city hall is that way.
Eun-su.
Get out.
Turn yourself in for the domestic violence
you've committed until now.
Enough with the attitude.
Turn the car around.
I've never hit you kids. Not once.
Do you know
how pathetic it feels to be a coward?
Why couldn't you have hit me too?
Then at least I'd have an excuse
for playing dumb about you beating Mom.
Shall I file a report?
Do you really think
they'd lock me up for my private affairs?
Get out.
What are you doing?
What do you think you're doing?
GANGNEUNG POLICE STATION
Stop that!
Hey, what's wrong with you?
Hey, Jo Eun-su.
I asked you not to do that.
What's wrong with you?
What were we even doing?
Everything's okay now.
Were those two even friends?
No, I've never seen
the two of them together.
Then what's with the theatrics?
Hui-su.
Hey, Hui-su.
I'm outside your place,
but I guess you're not home.
I went home to Gangneung,
and I just wanted to chat with you.
The doors are closing.
Hui-su!
Hui-su. It's me, Eun-su.
You're in there, aren't you?
What is it?
Why are you acting so strange?
Go, Eun-su. I'll call you later.
Jeez.
Why didn't you tap out?
And this happened to you?
A FEW HOURS AGO
Not me, but my friend.
Are you going to file a report?
Sorry?
Are you going to sue?
Officer Kim?
This is the Sinsa substation.
How can I help you?
It's almost like you're a restaurant
asking, "Table for how many?
What would you like to order?"
Didn't you hear him tap out?
Everyone across the room heard him.
Jo Eun-su.
No sparring for a month.
And no access to the gym for a month.
Let's play hide-and-seek.
-Who's "it"?
-Hush.
I'm sleepy, Eun-su.
Let me push you a few more times, okay?
Hey, Jo Eun-su!
Eun-su!
-Peace signs.
-Peace.
I feel silly.
One more with big smiles.
Now, three, two, one.
-Smile.
-Eun-su, get in here.
All right.
What's the big deal? It's fine.
I called to ask you
to switch my watch strap,
only to be summoned by a bar owner.
My apologies.
And thank you.
I'll repay you for the drinks.
As you should.
Did someone hit you?
You talked in your sleep
the entire ride back.
If you found out that someone close to you
was being abused, what would you…
Thank you so much for yesterday.
I have somewhere to be, so I've got to go.
Coming through.
Right.
JINGANG CHINESE MARKET
EUN-HYEOK
Eun-su.
I'm moving back home.
I requested a transfer.
Eun-hyeok.
Jong-gu's younger sibling
is a police officer.
They saw you and Dad.
When we were young,
we often hid in the closet together.
We weren't playing, were we?
It made no sense
for the both of us to hide together.
So Dad was "it."
You were just a kid too.
I'm sorry, Eun-su.
Why would you apologize? What for?
About Dad…
You did the right thing.
And don't worry about Mom anymore.
Get to work. Let's get rich.
HUI-SU, WHAT ARE YOU UP TO?
HAVE YOU HAD LUNCH?
THE WEATHER'S LOVELY, LOOK OUTSIDE
All done.
This is your receipt and authenticity card
for the watch strap.
And this is for the drinks from last time.
Thank you again.
I returned the watch to you
that day, right?
You owe me a meal.
As the domestic economy continues
to show signs of a slowdown,
there is a growing demand for government
to provide additional stimulus.
For trivial matters to fade away,
you should treat them as trivial.
What if it's not a trivial matter?
Then you let your inner psycho out of you.
Now the latest accident reports.
A woman tragically ended her life
by jumping in front of her husband's car.
The incident occurred in an upscale area
in Hannam-dong, Seoul,
when Kang threw herself in front of
her husband Kwon's imported SUV.
VICTIM OF ABUSE JUMPS IN FRONT OF CAR
Kwon is known to run a mid-sized company.
Her husband, Kwon,
insists that the incident was an accident…
VIP SALES LEE DONG-GYU
…but bruises and evidence of abuse
were found on her body…
Ms. Jo, have you seen the news?
Mrs. Kang Hui-yeon passed away.
What?
We're to head to the funeral home
with black funeral clothes for the family…
Ms. Jo?
Are you listening?
I thought you, Eun-su…
would be different.
MOM
Hey, Eun-su.
Why do you have Mom's phone?
Mom's washing her hair.
Okay.
I'll call again later.
HUI-SU
I looked the other way.
I need to go.
You're not going to say something stupid
like, "It's my fault she's dead," are you?
And how are you going to drive
when you're trembling?
I need to see her.
She should have killed her damn husband.
Why throw away your life
instead of living to see him off?
That motherfucking douchebag.
What happened to you?
Eun-su, you should go now.
Let's talk later.
Hui-su.
Hui-su, please don't! No!
Eun-su.
I want to end it all now.
No, Hui-su, you can't!
Please, no!
No!
No…
I don't want to die at his hands.
I have to end this myself.
Let's kill him.
We'll kill your husband.
Subtitle translation by: Jimin Choi